Muhammad Usama

| mdusama225@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/muhammad-usama | beyonddevops.engineer | github

KHI, Pakistan

SUMMARY

DevOps Engineer at Technyx System, Final year Software engineering student at UBIT. Production experience with AWS, and Azure skills in Container Technologies, Linux Administration, and CI/CD Integration and a desire to learn new things, Writer (blog.beyonddevops.engineer).

SKILLS

CI Tool: Jenkins, GitHub Contenirazation: Docker, Kubernetes

Configuration Management: Ansible, cloud formation **Scripting**: Python, Bash

Infrastructure as Code: Terraform Cloud: AWS, Azure

DevOps Tool: Jira, Azure DevOps Additional: System Administration,

EXPERIENCE

DevOps Engineer Jan 2023 - Current

Technys System | Pakistan, KHI | Technyx System

- Reduce the cost of existing infrastructure by 20 percent
- Set up infrastructure in AWS.
- Implement Continuous Integration and scalability for various projects

DevOps Engineer June 2022 - Aug 2022

Creative Chaos| Remote | https://creativechaos.co/

- Dockerize the microservice applications
- Build a CI CD pipeline in Jenkins for Flutter build and publish to AppCenter

EDUCATION

University Of Karachi | UBIT, KHI | https://uok.edu.pk/

Dec 2021 - Current

University Of Karachi | UBIT, KHI | https://uok.edu.pk/ Bachelor in Software Engineering

CERTIFICATE

Kubernetes Application Developer (CKAD) KodeCloud

Aug 2022

PROJECT

MERN Stack k8s Deployment k8s Deployment

- Deploy MERN stack Kubernetes into AWS EKS